Frank G. Speck Papers 1903-1950 Mss.Ms.Coll.126
American Philosophical Society
- Subcollection I. Frank G. Speck Papers, 1897-1950; 10 linear feet
  - Series II. Biographical Material, 1897-1950; 1.75 linear feet
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1942-1943; 2 items; Smith, Frank E., 1919-1984 (Box 20)
      Concerning his interest n Scatticook Indians and in Captivity narratives.
      F&S 3229
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1918-1919; 2 items; Smith, Harlan Ingersoll, 1872-1940 (Box 20)
      Concerning Iroquois material-culture specimens; Speck's aid to Indians wishing to see pots and pipes; pottery finds in Tadoussac region; British Columbia archaeology.
      F&S 1658
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1944; 2 items; Solenberger, Robert (Box 20)
      Concerning Tonawanda and Chippewa women who make baskets; gives their addresses.
      F&S 2515
    - to his mother, n.d.; 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 20)
      One letter is concerning his activities among Indians at Mohegan, CT. The other is regarind his activities in Summitville, Sullivan CO.
      F&S 2280
    - Notes on artifacts., 1912; 6 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 20)
      Found near Lake Abitibi and in the Nipissing district.
      F&S 373
    - Miscellaneous Reports, 1931-1939; 3 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 20)
      Consists of reports to University of Pennsylvania Research Committee on field work among Oklahoma Delaware, St. Francis Abenaki, Munsee and Six Nations Delaware, Tutelo, Cauga, 1931-1936; notebook of addresses and miscellaneous notes; list of Eskimo field trip, 1934, addresses. Outline, "The Indian as a Factor in American History, 1500-1900." Two-page list material culture data.
      F&S 914
    - The Indian as a Factor in American History, 1500-1900, 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 20)
      Outline.
    - Bibliography of Speck's Publications, 1942; 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 20)
      Two variations of Speck's publications as of 1942.
    - Comments on Lindquist's Red Man in the U.S., 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 20)
      Handwritten comments on the work.
    - Penobscot Ms., n.d.; 3 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 20)
      miscellaneous notes relating to the Penobscot Ms.
    - Biographical listing, n.d.; 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 20)
      Brief biographical outline for Speck.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1897; 3 items; Speck, Frank G. Jr. (Box 20)
      Relate to vacation in New York.
    - to Dr. ?, n.d.; 1 item; Speck? (Box 20)
      Inquires about the fate of his manuscript submitted for publication to the University Museum.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1915-1916; 2 items; Spinder, Herbert J. (Box 20)
      Christmas cards with Toltec designs on borders.
      F&S 2193
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1941-1942; 2 items; Staub, Peter (Box 20)
      Regarding obtaining North Carolina Cherokee masks and masks in general; list of masks sent to Peter Staub: two Eskimo, one Cherokee, one Tsimshian, one Iroquois, one Seneca, and one Cayuga.
      F&S 4332
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1918; 2 items; Swales, B. H. (Box 20)
      Concerning ethnohistoric materials and southestern ethnohistory. Sale of Indian-produced art goods.
      F&S 1279
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1937; 1 item; Swanton, John R. (Box 20)
      Comments on Specks "Catawba Medicines and Curative Practices."
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1924-1925; 3 items; Swarthmore College (Box 20)
      Letters of appointment.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1942; 1 item; Thayer, B. W. (Box 20)
      Concerning Ojibwa bead work found during Minnesota field trip.
      F&S 2521
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1921; 2 items; Thompson, B. A. (Box 20)
      Sends axehead and arrowheads found in southeastern Pennsylvania.
      F&S 2701
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1913-1915; 2 items; Tozzer, Alfred (Box 20)
      Letters regarding his opinion of Gordon.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1947-1948; 2 items; Traynor, Donald P. (Box 20)
      Thanks Speck for sending the book he requested. Replies to Speck's letter, and inquires of Speck what is needed to be an anthropologist.
    - "The Balsam Peaks: The Heart of the Southern Appalachians", n.d.; 1 item; Trotter, Spencer (Box 20)
      Typed paper.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1942; 2 items; Turner, G. E. S. (Box 20)
      Description of some moccasins in the Pitt Rivers Museum, Oxford University, for possible identification by Speck. Discussion of other items in the museum and comparison of moose hair embroidery with quillwork. Letterhead with name written, and empty envelopes.
      F&S 4334
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1945; 1 item; Tyler, Dorothy L. (Box 20)
      Regarding the galley proofs for one of Specks publications done by the Cranbrook Institute of Science.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1942-1947; 2 items; Unidentified correspondent (Box 20)
      Regarding payment and distribution of a publication by Speck and the writer. Relays comments by Sherwood Washburn of the work. Contacting Speck in advance of his visit.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1913-1945; 3 items; University Museum of the University of Pennsylvania (Box 20)
      Inquiring if Speck would be interested in using space in the Museum for office or lectures. Informing him he has been appointed a research fellow in the American Section.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1907-1909; 2 items; University of California (Box 20)
      Notifications of appointment
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1911-1932; 30 items; University of Pennsylvania. (Box 20)
      Letters of appointment. Regarding the budget for the Department of Anthropology. Letters from various departments of the University to Speck that include letters of appreciation, relating the the Museum Library, notifying him of appointments, and granting permission for various projects.
    - 1935-1946, 13 items; University of Pennsylvania - Misc. Material (Box 20)
      Receipts, class outlines, lecture notes, etc. Regarding the support by the University Museum to graduate students in Archaeology.
    - to Arthur Hobson Quinn, 1917; 1 item; University of Pennsylvania, Department of Anthropology (Box 20)
      Report on the Anthropology Department, and the courses taught.
    - National Research Council Report, n.d.; 1 item; University of Pennsylvania, Department of Anthropology (Box 20)
      Report of the work of the Department.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1937-1945; 2 items; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 20)
      Concerning usefulness of Speck's Naskapi material for comparative study of Algonkin languages; seeks article on process by which Algonkian languages become extinct; general discussion.
      F&S 366
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1943; 1 item; Walker, Abraham M. (Box 20)
      Regarding obtaining material on the Indians of Virginia. Mentions W. Carson Ryan.
      F&S 4890
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1943; 1 item; Wallace, Paul A. W. (Box 20)
      Concerning history of the Six Nations; mentions Cree tales (Wissakutchek) collected by Edward Ahenakew in Alberta.
      F&S 1804
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1947; 1 item; Walser, Richard (Box 20)
      Regarding the accuracy of material in Robert Strange, Eoneguski, or the Cherokee Chief (1939); the title is a variation of Yonaguska in the woks of Mooney and Hodge.
      F&S 4170
    - n.d., 2 items; Wampum (Box 20)
      Introductory copy of newsletter along with introductory letter from the editor, E. E. M. Joblin.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1927; 3 items; Ward, Christopher L. (Box 20)
      Regarding the printing of extra copies of Speck's Nanticoke study by the Historical Society of Delaware.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1913; 1 item; Warfield, J. O. (Box 20)
      Thanks Speck for his letter of the 26th, and states he has been working in a different direction. Consents to Speck giving his name to the Provost of the University in order to give his testimony.
    - to Frank G. Speck, n.d.; 1 item; Weaver's Community Shope (Box 20)
      invoice.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1915; 1 item; Weinberg's Aviary and Aquarium (Box 20)
      Reply to Speck's inquiry for reptiles and snakes.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1920; 1 item; Weitluner, R. J. (Box 20)
      Mentions Speck's field trip to Powhatan and Catawba Indians.
      F&S 523
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1940; 1 item; Wes (Box 20)
      Returns to Speck the copy of MacLeod's paper, and gives his comments on it.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1941; 1 item; White, Leslie A. (Box 20)
      Inquiring about William Christie MacLeod to teach for White and Mischa Titiev at the University of Michigan if they are on leave.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1926-1928; 19 items; White, Richard Jr. I (Box 20)
      White, a trader at North Labrador writes concerning specimens sent of Mantagnais-Naskapi and Eskimo Indian goods. Personal data; world affairs discussed. Principally from White to Speck, but a few from Speck.
      F&S 1344
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1930-1936; 55 items; White, Richard Jr. II (Box 20)
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1940-1948; 59 items; White, Richard Jr. III (Box 20)
    - The Indian and the Federal Government, 2 items; White, Stewart Edward (Box 20)
      Reproduction of White's paper for Specks Sociology 3 class at the University of Pennsylvania.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1927; 1 item; Wildens, Harry Emerson (Box 20)
      Thanks Speck for letting him audit his Negro course. Comments on the value of anthropology to sociologists.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1918; 1 item; Wilder, Harris H. (Box 20)
      Concerning place names; Penobscot translations.
      F&S 2947
    - The Origin of Indian Corn, 1944; 1 item; Wilkins, C.E. (Box 20)
      Cover sheet of a report for Speck's Athropology 1C class, with handwritten note by Wilkins on the reverse side.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1921; 1 item; Williams, Spencer F. (Box 20)
      Writer, a Seneca, seeks work.
      F&S 3631
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1935; 1 item; Wissler, Clark (Box 20)
      Invites Speck to become a memboer of editorial committee for new enlarged edition of the Handbook of American Indians. Sapir, Stirling, Kidder also invited.
      F&S 4340
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1946; 1 item; Wiswall, Richard Hall (Box 20)
      Informs Speck that he has been appointed honorary curator of American Indian Ethnology by the Peabody Museum of Salem.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1914; 1 item; Yoder, Hiram J. (Box 20)
      Regarding Speck's order for snakes.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1941; 1 item; Zimmerman, William (Box 20)
      Concerning Speck's report on the Houma; mentions notes on Alabama Creek.
      F&S 1580
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1943; 1 item; Zirkle, Conway, 1895-1972 (Box 20)
      Zirkle's comments on Darlington's letter regarding snakes swallowing their young in danger. Relates a story from his past.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1914-1918; 4 items; Zoological Society of Philadelphia (Box 20)
      Acknowledgement of gifts and notification of election to membership.
  - Series III. Photographs, 1904-1950; 572.97 Sp3
    - Algonquin, 1924-1937; 1-2(a-e)
      Other Finding Aids note
      Freeman guide, #4202b
    - Algonquin Council, 1924; 1-3(a-b)
      Freeman guide, #4602b
    - Annawan's rock, n.d.; 1-4(a)
      Freeman guide, #4598a
    - Apache, n.d.; 1-5(a-d)
    - Ashmolean Museum, 1955; 1-6(a-j)
    - Assiniboin, n.d.; 1-7(a-b)
    - Athabasca River, 1912-1913; 1-8(a)
      Freeman guide, #4143b
    - Batiscan River, P.Q., 1912-1913; 1-9(a)
    - Batiscan Summit, 1912-1913; 1-10(a)
    - Bead work, 1940-1941; 1-11(a)
    - Beothuk-Micmac, 1911; 1-12(a-f)
      Freeman guide, #4595a
    - Blackfoot, 1914; 1-13(a-d)
      Freeman guide, #4130a
    - Blood, n.d.; 1-14(a)
    - Bodmer, Karl: Engravings from his drawings of Indians, #1, 1935; 1-15(a-g)
      Freeman guide, #4682e
    - Bodmer, Karl: Engravings from his drawings of Indians, #2, 1935; 1-16(a-f)
    - Bodmer, Karl: Engravings from his drawings of Indians, #3, 1935; 1-17(a-f)
    - Bodmer, Karl: Engravings from his drawings of Indians, #4, 1935; 1-18(a-f)
    - Brazil: Mato Grosso, etc. #1, 1922-1932; 1-19(a-j)
      Freeman guide, #4759a
    - Brazil: Mato Grosso, etc. #2, 1922-1932; 1-20(a-j)
    - Brazil: Mato Grosso, etc. #3, 1922-1932; 1-21(a-j)
      - Ceremonial dance, 1932; 1-21-a
      - Ceremonial dress, 1932; 1-21-b
    - Brazil: Mato Grosso, etc. #4, 1922-1932; 1-22(a-j)
    - Brazil: Mato Grosso, etc. #5, 1922-1932; 1-23(a-j)
    - Brazil: Mato Grosso, etc. #6, 1922-1932; 1-24(a-e)
    - Brazil: Mato Grosso, etc. #7, 1922-1932; 1-25(a-f)
    - California Indians, 1907; 1-26(a-l)
      Freeman guide, #4132a
    - Canada and New England, 1-27(a-r)
      Freeman guide, #4143a
    - Catawba #1, 1906-1942; 1-28(a-k)
      Freeman guide, #4148a
    - Catawba #2, 1906-1942; 1-29(l-o)
    - Catawba #3, 1906-1942; 1-30(a-j)
    - Catawba #4, 1906-1942; 1-31(a-r)
    - Catawba #5, 1906-1942; 1-32(a-o)
    - Catawba #6, 1906-1942; 1-33(a-k)
    - Catawba #7, 1906-1942; 1-34(a-r)
    - Catawba #8, 1906-1942; 1-35(a-k)
    - Catawba #9, 1906-1942; 1-36(a-q)
    - Catawba #10, 1906-1942; 1-37(a-h)
    - Catawba #11, 1906-1942; 1-38(a-i)
    - Catawba, Cherokee, and Machapunga (North Carolina), #1, 1906-1942; 1-40(a-r)
    - Catawba, Cherokee, and Machapunga (North Carolina), #2, 1906-1942; 1-41(a-r)
    - Catawba methods of coiling, n.d.; 1-42(a)
    - Catawba pipes (pottery), 1906-1942; 1-43(a-c)
    - Catawba pots, n.d.; 1-44(a-d)
    - Catawba potters, 1906-1942; 1-45(a-c)
      - Mrs. Eliza Gordon, 1944; 1-45-b
    - Catawba pottery, n.d.; 1-46(a-e)
    - Catawba pottery (cross-sections), n.d.; 1-47(a-b)
    - Catawba pottery (small pieces), n.d.; 1-39(a)
    - Catawba pottery making, n.d.; 1-48(a-h)
    - Catawba pottery making (techniques), n.d.; 1-49(a-d)
    - [Catawba] pottery making tools, n.d.; 1-50(a-b)
    - Catawba pottery pieces, n.d.; 1-51(a-b)
    - Catawba vases, n.d.; 1-52(a-b)
    - Catawba vessels, n.d.; 1-53((a)
    - Cayuga, 1949; 1-54(a-l)
      Freeman guide, #4714a
    - Cayuga--Davey, Cuthbert, 1949; 1-55(a-b)
    - Cayuga--Davey, Jenima Hess (Mrs. Cuthbert Davey), 1949; 1-56(a)
    - Cayuga--Long House (outside), 1933; 1-57(a)
    - Central and South America, 2-1(a-f)
      Freeman guide, #4149a
    - Cherokee #1, 1915-1948; 2-2(a-v)
      Freeman guide, #4162a
      - Cherokee child, clay pot, basket, 2-2-a
      - Cherokee man holding child, 2-2-u-4
    - Cherokee #2, 1915-1948; 2-3(a-n)
      - Cherokee store, interior, 2-3-f-1
    - Cherokee #3, 1915-1948; 2-4(a-u)
      - Cherokee dancing, men in masks, 2-4-l
      - Cherokee women dancing, 2-4-n
    - Cherokee #4, 1915-1948; 2-5(a-l)
      - Cherokee dwellings, 1915-1948; 2-5-h
    - Cherokee and Catawba nations--map, 2-6(a)
    - Cherokee mortars and pestles, 1921; 2-7(a-b)
    - Cherokee Mother, with child on back, n.d.; 2-8(a)
    - Cherokee pottery stamp paddles, 1915; 2-9(a)
    - Cherokee vessel, n.d.; 2-10(a)
    - Cherokee--Welch, Mrs. Maude, n.d.; 2-11(a-c)
    - Cheyenne, n.d.; 2-12(a-b)
      Freeman guide, #4171a
    - Chickahominy #1, 1939-1948; 2-13(a-l)
      Freeman guide, #4687a
      - Temporry Birch-Bark wigwam, 2-13-g
    - Chickahominy #2, 1939-1948; 2-14(a-q)
    - Chickahominy #3, 1939-1948; 2-15(a-w)
    - Chickahominy #4, 1939-1948; 2-16(a-m)
    - Chickahominy #5, 1939-1948; 2-17(n-t)
    - Chipewyan, 1912-1913; 2-18(a-e)
    - Choctaw beaded belts, 1935-1946; 2-19(a-b)
      Freeman guide, #4179b
    - Choctaw Indians, ball playing, 2-20(a-b)
      Freeman guide, #4179a
    - Comanche war shield, 1925; 2-21(a)
      Freeman guide, #4682a
    - Cooke, Chas. A., 1949; 2-22(a-b)
    - Cornplanter, Jesse J.--drawings, 1937; 2-23(a-g)
      Freeman guide, #4377a
      - Corn husk dolls, 1937; 2-23-a
    - Cornplanter, Jesse J.--naked bear drawings, 1937; 2-24(a-d)
    - Cree #1, 1908-1940; 2-25(a-m)
      Freeman guide, #4188a
    - Cree #2, 1908-1940; 2-26(n-z)
    - Cree #3, 1908-1940; 2-27(a-m)
    - Cree #4, 1908-1940; 2-28(a-i)
    - Creek #1, 1904-1941; 2-29(a-o)
      Freeman guide, #4546a
    - Creek #2, 1904-1941; 2-30(a-l)
    - Creek #3, 1904-1941; 2-31(m-x)
    - Creek and Yuchi #1, 1904-1941; 2-32(a-q)
    - Creek and Yuchi #2, 1904-1941; 2-33(a-y)
    - Creek mortar, 1904-1941; 2-34(a)
    - Crow, 1938-1948; 2-35(a-g)
      Freeman guide, #4682b
    - Cuna (Columbia), 1947; 2-36(a)
      Freeman guide, #4149b
    - Delaware #1, 1910-1945; 2-37(a-l)
      Freeman guide, #4213a
    - Delaware #2, 1910-1945; 2-38(m-z)
      - Witapanoxwe, 1910-1945; 2-38-w
    - Delaware #3, 1910-1945; 2-39(a-o)
    - Delaware #4, 1910-1945; 2-40(p-q)
    - Delaware--War eagle, n.d.; 2-41(a)
    - Eskimo (Alaska) #1, 1901-1947; 3-1(a-i)
      Freeman guide, #4251a
    - Eskimo (Alaska) #2, 1901-1947; 3-2(a-h)
    - Eskimo (Alaska) #3, 1901-1947; 3-3(a-h)
    - Eskimo (Alaska) #4, 1901-1947; 3-4(a-h)
    - Eskimo (Baffin Land), 1901-1947; 3-5(a)
    - Eskimo (Keewatin), 1901-1947; 3-6(a-l)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #1, 1901-1947; 3-7(a-y)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #2, 1901-1947; 3-8(a-l)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #3, 1901-1947; 3-9(m-z)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #4, 1901-1947; 3-10(a-o)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #5, 1901-1947; 3-11(a-l)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #6, 1901-1947; 3-12(a-m)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #7, 1901-1947; 3-13(a-p)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #8, 1901-1947; 3-14(a)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #9, 1901-1947; 3-15(a-j)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #10, 1901-1947; 3-16(a-t)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #11, 1901-1947; 3-17(a-f)
    - Eskimo (Labrador) #12, 1901-1947; 3-18(a-h)
    - Eskimo (Southampton Island) #1, 1901-1947; 3-19(a-p)
    - Eskimo (Southampton Island) #2, 1901-1947; 3-20(a-p)
    - Eskimo--sled dogs (Labrador), 1901-1947; 3-21(a-m)
    - Fadden, Ray: Contributions of the American Indians, 3-22(a)
    - Gabor, Ray and Bob. Handsome Lake drawings, 3-23(a-c)
      Freeman guide, #4388a
    - Hare Indians (a), 1961-1962; 3-24; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
      Freeman guide, #4234a
    - Hare Indians (b), 1961-1962; 3-25; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (c), 1961-1962; 3-26; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (d), 1961-1962; 3-27; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (e), 1961-1962; 3-28; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (f), 1961-1962; 3-29; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (g), 1961-1962; 3-30; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (h), 1961-1962; 3-31; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (i), 1961-1962; 3-32; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (j), 1961-1962; 3-33; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (k), 1961-1962; 3-34; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Hare Indians (l), 1961-1962; 3-35; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - Heckewelder Photos, 1955; 3-36(a-h); Wallace, Paul A. W.
      Freeman guide, #4244a
    - Heckewelder Illustration, 1955; 3-37(a)
      Wallace, Paul A. W. -- Pictorial works
    - Hopi girl, 1908-1938; 3-39(a)
      Freeman guide, #4351a
    - Hopi man, Moki, 1908-1938; 3-40(a)
    - Houma #1, 1936-1941; 4-1(a-o)
      Freeman guide, #4364a
    - Houma #2, 1936-1941; 4-2(a-v)
    - Houma #3, 1936-1941; 4-3(a-o)
    - Houma #4, 1936-1941; 4-4(a-f)
    - Houma #5, 1936-1941; 4-5(a-q)
      - Houma woman, 1936-1941; 4-5-b
    - Houma #6, 1936-1941; 4-6(a-u)
    - Houma #7, 1936-1941; 4-7(a-m)
    - Houma #8, 1936-1941; 4-8(n-y)
    - Houma #9, 1936-1941; 4-9(a-b)
    - Houma #10, 1936-1941; 4-10(a-n)
    - Houma #11, 1936-1941; 4-11(a-v)
    - Huron, 1913-1952; 4-12(a-c)
      Freeman guide, #4397a
    - Indian encampment, 4-13(a)
    - Indian races of North and South America: Illustrations #1, 1855; 4-14(a-j)
      Freeman guide, #4291a
    - Indian races of North and South America: Illustrations #2, 1855; 4-15(a-i)
    - Indian races of North and South America: Illustrations #3, 1855; 4-16(a-j)
      - Cherokee settlement, 1855; 4-16-h
    - Indian races of North and South America: Illustrations #4, 1855; 4-17(a-h)
    - Indian scene, 1940-1955; 4-18(a)
    - Indian Village (Oklahoma), 4-19(a)
      Freeman guide, #4612a
      - Delaware village, 1910-1945; 4-19-a
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #1, 4-20(a-g)
      Freeman guide, #4291b
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #2, 4-21(a-h)
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #3, 4-22(a-h)
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #4, 4-23(a-h)
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #5, 4-24(a-h)
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #6, 4-25(a-h)
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #7, 4-26(a-e)
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #8, 4-27(a-f)
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #9, 4-28(a-e)
    - Indians of North and South America: Miscellaneous Illustrations #10, 4-29(a-e)
    - Iowa and Ponca dancers, 1935; 4-30(a)
      Freeman guide, #4282e
    - Iroquois #1, 1913-1952; 4-31(a-d)
    - Iroquois #2, 1913-1952; 4-32(a-g)
    - Iroquois #3, 1912-1952; 4-33(a-p)
    - Iroquois: Men in false face, 1913-1952; 4-34(a)
      - Men in false faces, 1913-1952; 4-34-a
    - Johnson, Frederick #1, 1929; 4-35(a-l)
      Freeman guide, #4188b
      Montagnais Indians; Naskapi Indians
    - Johnson, Frederick #2, 1929; 4-36(a-l)
      - Man constructing a canoe, 4-36-k
      - Detail view of canoe, 4-36-l
    - Johnson, Frederick #3, 1929; 4-37(a-l)
    - Johnson, Frederick #4, 1929; 4-38(a-l)
      - Unidentified Innu man, 4-38-e
    - Johnson, Frederick #5, 1929; 4-39(a-j)
      - Woman making splint basket, 4-39-a
      - Three young children standing with three babies in cradleboards, 4-39-d
      - Two men standing in front of a house, 4-39-g
    - Kansa (Kaw), 1904; 4-40(a-j)
      Freeman guide, #4231a
    - Kickapoo house, 1932; 4-41(a-b)
      Freeman guide, #4256a
    - Kiowa (Apache), n.d.; 4-42(a)
    - Kutenai, etc., 1947-1948; 4-43(a-m)
      Freeman guide, #4682d
    - Lake George, NY--Indian village, 4-44(a-d)
    - Logan, Chief Joseph, 1949; 4-45(a)
      Onondaga Indians
    - Logan, Mrs. Joseph, 1949; 4-46(a)
    - Maricopa man, n.d.; 5-1(a)
      Freeman guide, #4698b
    - Mattaponi #1, 1939-1940; 5-2(a-k)
      Freeman guide, #4687b
    - Mattaponi #2, 1939-1940; 5-3(a-g)
    - Mattaponi #3, 1939-1940; 5-4(a-m)
    - Mesa Verde, 1910; 5-5(a-f)
      Freeman guide, #4796a
    - Mexico, 1894-1923; 5-6(a-g); Rutter, Charles A.
      Freeman guide, #4520a
    - Micmac #1, 1913-1947; 5-7(a-j)
      Freeman guide, #4527a
    - Micmac #2, 1913-1947; 5-8(a-l)
    - Micmac and Newfoundland #1, 1913-1947; 5-9(a-l)
    - Micmac and Newfoundland #2, 1913-1947; 5-10(m-w)
    - Miscellaneous #1, n.d.; 5-11(a-n)
    - Miscellaneous #2, n.d.; 5-12(a-d)
    - Miscellaneous #3, n.d.; 5-13(a-p)
    - Miscellaneous #4, n.d.; 5-14(a-q)
    - Mississippi, Indian tribes of the lower, 1909; 5-15(a); Swanton, John R.
    - Mohawk, 1925-1945; 5-16(a-e)
      Freeman guide, #4536a
    - Mohegan #1, 1909-1932; 5-17(a-g)
      Freeman guide, #4539a
    - Mohegan #2, 1909-1932; 5-18(a-o)
    - Mohegan #3, 1909-1932; 5-19(a-d)
    - Mohegan #4, 1909-1932; 5-20(a-c)
    - Mohegan--mortar and pestle, 1914; 5-21(a)
    - Montagnais-Naskapi #1, 1908-1941; 5-22(a-j)
    - Montagnais-Naskapi #2, 1908-1941; 5-23(k-u)
    - Montagnais-Naskapi #3, 1908-1941; 5-24(a-q)
      - Bononi Mak, 1908-1941; 5-24-h
    - Montagnais-Naskapi #4, 1908-1941; 5-25(a-g)
    - Montagnais-Naskapi #5, 1908-1941; 5-26(a-k)
      - Montagnais woman, with child in rabbit-skin sack, Lake St. John, Quebec, 5-26-c
      - Montagnais woman with child in cloth attire, Lake St. John, Quebec, 1913; 5-26-e
      - Unidentified men with sled and dogs, 5-26-f
      - Display of Naskapi attire in the National Museum of Copenhagen, 5-26-j
    - Montagnais-Naskapi #6, 1908-1941; 5-27(a-r)
    - Montagnais-Naskapi #7, 1908-1941; 5-28(a-v)
      - Unidentified men and boy, 5-28-e